What exactly is artificial intelligence?
We speak of AI when computer systems perform
that usually require human intelligence.
This includes, for example, recognizing
making decisions or engaging in dialogue.
To do this, the AI systems must be equipped
knowledge and experience.
This can be achieved in two ways.
You can program each individual instruction
that the machine solves the task step
step.
This is comparable to a cooking recipe
assembly instructions.
Alternatively, you can use programs that
from data themselves.
This enables them to detect relevant information,
conclusions or make predictions.
This is known as machine learning.
We all have probably dealt with AI at
point in our lives.
When we watch films, listen to music or
online.
AI gives us recommendations about what
might like.
AI is capable of converting spoken language
text and translating it into other languages.
AI is a central component of robotics.
Robots make our everyday lives easier
take on strenuous activities.
Self-driving vehicles recognise their
through AI and can react to it.
AI is becoming increasingly important
medicine.
It supports doctors when diagnosing diseases.
Also, more and more patients use AI-based
for initial diagnosis.
In the educational sector, AI helps to
learning activities,
for example, on digital learning platforms.
AI is becoming increasingly important.
Once we understand how AI works, we can
gauge where it can support everyday activities
at home and at work, and where we would
make our own decisions.
AI will not replace humans, but it is
better and better at supporting us.
For this, we need an AI-competent society.