What exactly is artificial intelligence?
We speak of AI when computer systems
perform tasks that usually require human
intelligence.
This includes, for example, recognizing
images, making decisions, or engaging in
dialogue.
To do this, the AI systems must be
equipped with knowledge and experience.
This can be achieved in two ways.
You can program each individual
instruction so that the machine solves the
task step by step.
This is comparable to a cooking recipe or
assembly instructions.
Alternatively, you can use programs that
learn from data themselves.
This enables them to detect relevant
information, draw conclusions, or make
predictions.
This is known as machine learning.
We all have probably dealt with AI at some
point in our lives.
When we watch films, listen to music, or
shop online, AI gives us recommendations
about what we might like.
AI is capable of converting spoken
language into text and translating it into
other languages.
AI is a central component of robotics.
Robots make our everyday lives easier or
take on strenuous activities.
Self-driving vehicles recognize their
environment through AI and can react to
it.
AI is becoming increasingly important
within medicine.
It supports doctors when diagnosing
diseases.
Also, more and more patients use AI-based
apps for initial diagnosis.
In the educational sector, AI helps to
individualize learning activities,
for example on digital learning platforms.
AI is becoming increasingly important.
Once we understand how AI works, we can
better gauge where it can support everyday
activities
at home and at work, and where we would
rather make our own decisions.
AI will not replace humans, but it is
getting better and better at supporting
us.
For this, we need an AI competent society.